tattoojoy.com 2006-11-16

# TattooJoy.com - Privacy Statement

The foundation of TattooJoy.com is based on trust and it is for this reason that we hold a great deal of respect for the privacy of our users. In order to provide a richer feature set and to provide a more personalized user experience on the TattooJoy.com Web site, we collect information from our users. This Privacy Policy describes in detail the information we collect and how it is used and disseminated to provide a more fulfilling user experience. 

**The Information We Collect:**   
As you use our services, our servers will automatically track certain information about you. This information includes your IP address, the URL that you just came from, which URL you go to next, which browser you are using, and which operating system you are using. This is not unique to the TattooJoy.com website as many existing sites automatically collect this information.   
Your IP address will be used solely for administrative purposes and will not be linked to any personally identifiable information. We also use cookies on certain pages of our site, and for services requiring registration. This is done primarily for your benefit as cookies allow you to log on only once per session. Most cookies are automatically deleted at the end of a session. In addition, many browsers offer users the option of declining cookies. If you do not wish to accept cookies, please modify the settings in your browser. Your browser must be set to accept cookies if you wish to use the TattooJoy.com services available only to registered members. 

**Our Use of Your Information:**   
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site.   
Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information. Your IP address may be used in order to enforce certain policies within our User Agreement.   
Our site uses cookies mainly for the purpose of delivering content specific to your interests, and to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you access a registered member only page.   
Cookies may also be used for other purposes at times.   
Our online surveys at times ask visitors for contact information such as their email address. We use contact data from our surveys to send the user information about our company.   
Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; please see the Your Ability to Opt-Out section below.   
We run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information such as their email address, full name, and street address.   
We use contact data from our contests to contact our winners and to send users information about our company. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; please see the Your Ability to Opt-Out section below.   
This site contains links to many other tattoo-related sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. Since TattooJoy.com does not control the privacy policies of third parties, you are subject to the privacy customs and policies of that third party. We encourage you to ask questions and review their stated privacy policies before you disclose your personal information to others. 

**Our Policies Regarding the Disclosure of Your Information:**   
We do not sell, rent, trade or otherwise share any personally identifiable information about our users to any third party. This includes, but is not limited to the names, addresses, email addresses, and phone numbers of our users. In addition, we will not disclose any personally identifiable financial or security related personally identifiable information such as credit card numbers and or passwords.   
We do aggregate broad demographic information on our user base, which we disclose to our current and prospective advertisers. In addition, this aggregated data is used internally for promotional purposes.   
We use the information about the interests our users to increase the effectiveness of our marketing and promotional efforts and to customize our site's content and layout. We believe these uses allow us to create a personalized product that better satisfies our users needs.   
We may also use information about you to deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests, such as targeted banners. To participate in our message center, users are given the opportunity to create a profile that may be viewed by other users. Users are given the option when entering this information to make it viewable by other users or request that it remain private. If the user chooses to opt-in to this option of disclosing their information to third parties or other users, then the user may receive promotional items. Unfortunately, we cannot ensure the absolute privacy of any personally identifiable user information.   
For example, we may be forced to disclose information to government and/or law enforcement agencies or third parties under certain circumstances.   
TattooJoy.com cooperates with all law enforcement inquiries and reserves the right to reveal your identity (or whatever information we know about you) in the event of a complaint or legal action arising from your use of the services or features on the TattooJoy.com website.   
In addition, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Therefore, although we make it a practice not to disclose any personally identifiable information to any third party, we do not promise that your personally identifiable information or private communications will remain private. 

**Your Control of Your Password:**   
You may not disclose your password to any third party.   
If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personally identifiable information. In addition, you may run the risk of another user accessing your password and using it to falsely represent your identity. If you have reason to believe that your password has been compromised for any reason, TattooJoy.com strongly recommends that you immediately change your password. 

**Your Ability to Review and Change Your Personally Identifiable Information:**   
You may at any time review and change your personally identifiable information at TattooJoy.com.   
This information includes but is not limited to your email address, street address, city, state, zip code, country, daytime phone number, password, or credit card number and expiration date.   
To change this information, the user must log on and click the "preferences" link on the bottom of the TattooJoy.com pages. 

**Your Participation in our Message Center:**   
This site makes forums and message boards available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information in any of these public forums.   
In the course of using the services at TattooJoy.com you may be exposed to personally identifiable information of other users. Under no circumstances may you disclose personally identifiable information about another user to any third party without the consent of TattooJoy.com and the consent of such other user.   
Users are not permitted to add another TattooJoy.com user to your email list without that user's permission.   
TattooJoy.com does not tolerate spam, and we reserve the right to suspend the registration of any user who sends unsolicited email to our other users.   
If you choose to opt-in to allowing other users to view your email address when registering, you should use discretion. While we do not tolerate spam, we are not in a position to control the practices of all of our other visitors. If you believe that you have received unsolicited email from an TattooJoy.com user, please notify us at privacy@tattoojoy.com. 

**Our Security Measures:**   
TattooJoy.com uses industry standard efforts such as firewalls and Secure Socket Layers to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information. However, even the most robust security systems are not foolproof and users should consider this when revealing any personally identifiable information to any party over any form of media. 

**Your Ability to Opt-Out:**   
Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about the visitor.   
However, if the user decides at any time that s/he no longer wishes to receive future communications users may remove their information from our database by sending an email to remove@tattoojoy.com. 

**Contacting our Web Site:**   
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, or the privacy practices of TattooJoy.com, you can contact the company by sending an e-mail to privacy@tattoojoy.com.
